A Finding Aid to the Stendahl Art Galleries Records, 1907-1971, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
Stendahl Art Galleries records
1907-1971
Archives of American Art
Stendahl Art Galleries
AAA.stenartg
Archival Resource Key
7.5 Linear feet
The records of the Los Angeles Stendahl Art Galleries measure 7.5 linear feet and date from 1907 to 1971. The collection is comprised of administrative and financial files, correspondence, exhibition files, and subject files on numerous artists, organizations, and other art-related topics. There is one scrapbook of clippings on the artist Edgar Payne.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is temporarily closed to researchers due to archival processing and digitization. Contact Reference Services for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Stendahl Art Galleries records were donated by Alfred Stendahl in 1976. An album of clippings was donated by Stendahl in 1995 via Nancy Moure.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 4 series.
Missing Title
Series 1: Administrative and Financial Files, 1923-1957 (0.4 linear feet; Box 1)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1923-1968 (2.0 linear feet; Box 1-3)
Series 3: Exhibition Files, circa 1921-1967 (0.4 linear feet; Box 3)
Series 4: Subject Files, 1907-1971 (4.6 linear feet; Box 3-8, OV 9)
Scope and Contents
The records of the Los Angeles Stendahl Art Galleries measure 7.5 linear feet and date from 1907 to 1971. The collection is comprised of administrative and financial files, correspondence, exhibition files, and subject files on numerous artists, organizations, and other art-related topics. There is one scrapbook of clippings on the artist Edgar Payne.
Administrative and financial files concern advertising, publicity, consignments, inventory, purchases, sales, leases, and biographical information on Earl Stendahl.
The bulk of the correspondence is pre-World War II and is fairly extensive. It is with artists, organizations, collectors, art historians,and galleries. Signicant correspondents include Alexander Archipenko, Federico Beltran-Masses, Alexander Calder, Federico Cantú, Jean Charlot, Couvoisier Galleries, José de Creeft, Demotte Inc., Jerome Eddy, Lillian Genthe, Arthur Hill Gilbert, George B. Guthrie, Rockwell Kent, Louis Kronberg, Gisella Loeffler, Carlos Mérida, Isamu Noguchi, Walter Pach, Diego Rivera, Waler Elmer Schofield, David Alfaro Siquieros, Ladislas Szecsi, Wildenstein & Company, and many others.
Files are found for about ten exhibitions, including Etching and Engravings by the Old Masters (1921), Airview Paintings (1930), American Landscape Art (1930), Arts of New Guinea (1964), and for exhibitions of Emil Gelhaar, Wassily Kandinsky, Sydney Laurence, and Roberto Montenegro.
Subject files are found for numerous artists, art topics, galleries, and foundations. Most of the files consist of printed materials, but there is correspondence and additional primary source material found in files for Nicolai Ivanovich Feshin, the Thomas Gilcrease Foundation, Armin Hansen, Joseph Kleitsch, Aston Knight, José Clemente Orozco, Edgar Payne, Ralph M. Pearson, Pablo Picasso, William Ritschel, Diego Rivera, Ethel B. Rose, Guy Rose, Walter Elmer Schofield, David Alfaro Siquieros, Ladislas Szecsi, William Wendt, and Ignacio Zuloaga.
Biographical / Historical
Earl Stendahl established Stendahl Art Galleries in 1911 in Los Angeles, California.
Earl Stendahl (1887-1966) came to Southern California from a small town in Wisconsin. He began showing young Los Angeles artists at his downtown restaurant, The Black Cat Café. He opened his gallery in The Ambassador Hotel on Wilshire Boulevard and organized shows focusing primarily on California Impressionists of the early twentieth century, including Edgar Payne, Guy Rose, William Wendt, Nicolai Fechin, and Joseph Kleitsch.
Stendahl Art Galleries also began to sell European and Latin American modern art. In 1939, Stendahl hosted one of only two non-museum exhibitions of Pablo Picasso's masterwork, Guernica, to benefit Spanish War orphans.
As early as 1935 Stendahl began promoting ancient artifacts from Mexico and Central America. Stendahl's first client for pre-Columbian art and artifacts was noted collector Walter Arensberg. Stendahl and the Arensburgs became friends and Stendahl helped the Arensburgs build one of the most significant collections in the U.S.
The galleries are currently owned by Ronald W. Dammann, Stendahl's grandson.
Existence and Location of Copies
Portions of the collection are available on 35 mm microfilm reels 2716-2725 at the Archives of American Art offices and through interlibrary loan. Researchers should note that the arrangement of the material described in the container inventory does not reflect the arrangement of the collection on microfilm.
Art -- New Guinea; Latino and Latin American artists; Landscape painting; Prints; Gallery records; Scrapbooks; Art, American; Art, Modern -- 20th century -- California -- Los Angeles; Art galleries, Commercial -- California; Siqueiros, David Alfaro, 1896-1974; Picasso, Pablo, 1881-1973; Kent, Rockwell, 1882-1971; Gilbert, Arthur Hill, 1894-1970; Rose, Ethel Boardman, 1871-1946; Rivera, Diego, 1886-1957; Thomas Gilcrease Institute of American History and Art; Pearson, Ralph M., 1883-1958; Rose, Guy, 1867-1925; Demotte, inc. (New York, N.Y.); Couvoisier Galleries; Montenegro, Roberto, 1887-1968; Pach, Walter, 1883-1958; Wildenstein and Company (New York, N.Y.); De Creeft, José, 1884-1982; Noguchi, Isamu, 1904-1988; Loeffler, Gisella, 1900-; Stendahl, Earl L.; Laurence, Sydney, 1868-1940; Kandinsky, Wassily, 1866-1944; Calder, Alexander, 1898-1976; Cantú, Federico, 1908-1989; Guthrie, George B.; Archipenko, Alexander, 1887-1964; Beltrán-Masses, Federico, 1885-1949; Genth, Lillian Mathilde, 1876-1953; Wendt, William, 1865-1946; Ritschel, William, 1864-1949; Hansen, Armin C. (Armin-Carl), 1886-1957; Payne, Edgar A. (Edgar Alwin), 1882-1947; Knight, Aston, 1873-1948; Kronberg, Louis, 1872-1965; Gelhaar, Emil; Feshin, Nikolaĭ Ivanovich, 1881-1955; Szecsi, Ladislas; Schofield, Walter Elmer, 1867-1944; Charlot, Jean, 1898-1979; Kleitsch, Joseph, 1885-1931; Zuloaga, Ignacio, 1870-1945; Orozco, José Clemente, 1883-1949; Mérida, Carlos, 1891-1984; Eddy, Jerome
- Administrative and Financial Files, 1923-1957; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; 0.4 Linear feet Box 1
  Scope and Contents
  Files document advertising and publicity, consignments, inventory, purchases, sales, prices, lease agreements, and biographical information on Earl Stendahl.
  - Advertising, 1927-1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Auction, Private Collection of Stendahl, 1931; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Biographical Material for Stendahl, 1928-1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Consignments, 1935-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  - Inventory, Joseph Kleitsch, 1923-1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Lease Agreements, 1922-1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Price Lists, 1936-1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Project, American Miniature Museum of Art, 1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Publicity, circa 1925-1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 11-13)
  - Purchase of George Inness Painting, 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Sales, 1935-1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Sales, Nicolai Fechin, 1932-1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, 1923-1968; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; 2 Linear feet Boxes 1-3
  The majority of correspondence is between Earl Stendahl and various artists and organizations regarding loans of artwork, sales and purchases, and artists' accounts. Correspondents include Alexander Archipenko, Federico Beltran-Masses, Federico Cantú, Jean Charlot, Couvoisier Galleries, Demotte Inc., Jerome Eddy, Lillian Genthe, Arthur Hill Gilbert, George B. Guthrie, Rockwell Kent, Carlos Mérida, Isamu Noguchi, and Ladislas Szecsi. Also, an illustrated letter from Gisella Loeffler to Stendahl can be found. Some files may include financial and printed material.
  - General, A-Z, 1927-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 17-19)
  - Ainslie Galleries, 1928-1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Ara, Badger Dusonovich Kosich, circa 1931; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Archipenko, Alexander, 1928-1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Barr, William, 1930-1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Beltran-Masses, Federico, 1930s; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Birren, Joseph, 1923-1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Bonetti, Pascal, 1930-1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Botkin, Henry A., 1937-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Buchholz Gallery, 1943-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Calder, Alexander, 1964-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Cantu, Federico, 1939-1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Charlot, Jean, 1934-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - City of Paris Dry Goods Company, 1934-1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Corbino, Jon, 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Courvoisier Galleries, 1931-1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Coutts, Gordon, 1928-1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Demotte, Inc., 1930-1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Eddy, Jerome, circa 1934-1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Engdahl, Paul, 1935-1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - English, Harold, circa 1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Fulop, Karoly, 1930-1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Gage, George E., 1930-1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Gambee, Martin, circa 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Garber, Daniel, 1932-1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Gardena High School, 1932-1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Gaspard, Leon, 1931-1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Genth, Lillian, 1928-1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Gilbert, Arthur Hill, 1927-1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Griffith, William A., 1929-1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Groesbeck, Dan Sayre, 1926-1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Groll, Albert L., 1927-1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - S & G Gump Company, 1932-1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Guthrie, George B., 1933-1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Handley, Hester Merwin, 1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Hering, Georg, 1929-1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Kaufmann, Arthur, 1938-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Kent, Rockwell, 1928-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Kronberg, Louis, 1929-1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Lasky, Bessie, 1934-1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Loeffler, Gisella, circa 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Merida, Carlos, 1934-1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Modern Institute of Art, 1948-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Mora, Fluis, 1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Museo Nazionale D'Arte Orientale, 1963-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1936-1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Noguchi, Isamu, circa 1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Nash, Willard, 1933-1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Nierendorf Gallery, 1940-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Owles, Alfred, 1938-1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Paalen, Alice Rahon, 1944-1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Pach, Walter, circa 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Parshall, Dewitt, 1935-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Poland, Reginald, 1933-1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Re: Rembrandt, circa 1930-1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Rombold, Hugo, 1931-1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Russell, Charles, 1923-1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Sample, Paul Starrett, 1931-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Scott, James Andrew Neptune, 1930-1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Sekido, Yoshida, circa 1931; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Skaling, Audrey, 1944-1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Symons, Gardner, 1927-1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Szecsi, Ladislas, 1936-1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Taubes, Frederic, circa 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Ufer, Walter, 1929-1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Van Ryder, Jack, 1929-1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Vonnoh, Robert, 1926-1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Wadler, Ruth C., 1926-1931; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Walpole, Hugh, 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Warshawsky, Abel G., 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Wenger, John, 1927-1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Werner, Fritz, 1932-1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Wildenstein & Company, 1934-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
  - Williams, Frederick Ballard, 1929-1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Wood, Grant, 1935-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Woodward, Stanley, 1936-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Exhibition Files, circa 1921-1967; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 0.4 Linear feet Box 3
  Files for exhibitions consist of correspondence, exhibition announcements and catalogs, price lists, artist statements, and exhibition schedules. Exhibitions include Etching and Engravings by the Old Masters (1921), Airview Paintings (1930), American Lanscape Art (1930), National Museums of France Atelier Works (1931), Arts of New Guinea (1964), and multiple exhibitions of French modern painters that included the works of Marc Chagall. Additionally, files for exhibitions of work by Emil Gelhaar, Wassily Kandinsky, Sydney Laurence, and Roberto Montenegro are in this series.
  - Schedules, 1942-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Group Exhibitions, 1923-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Etchings and Engravings by the Old Masters (1921), circa 1921; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - "French Modern Painters," Multiple Exhibitions (1930s), Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
  - Airview Paintings (1930), Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - American Landscape Art (1930), circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - A Farewell to Alaska (1931), Sydney Laurence Exhibition, 1927-1931; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - National Museums of France Atelier Works (1931), Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Paintings by Emil Gelhaar (1931), Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Wassily Kandinsky 1903-1933 (1936), Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Paintings by Roberto Montenegro (1937), circa 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Arts of New Guinea (1964), 1962-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Subject Files, 1907-1971; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 4.8 Linear feet Boxes 3-8, OV 9
  Files on artists, topics, and organizations of interest to Stendahl are largely made up of printed materials, but some notes, writings, financial material, and additional correspondence can be found in this series. Included are files for James Bordrero, Nicolai Ivanovich Feshin, Thomas Gilcrease Foundation, Armin Hansen, Joseph Kleitsch, Aston Knight, José Clemente Orozco, Ralph M. Pearson, Pablo Picasso, José Martinez Pinazo, William Ritschel, Diego Rivera, Ethel B. Rose, Guy Rose, Walter Elmer Schofield, David Alfaro Siquieros, Ladislas Szecsi, William Wendt, and Ignacio Zuloaga, and others. A scrapbook of clippings is included in files for Edgar Payne and painted designs are in files for Ralph M. Pearson.
  - General, A-L, 1924-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 19-29)
  - General, L, 1921-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - General, M-N, 1924-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - General, M-N, 1925-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - General, M-N, 1934-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - General, O-P, 1927-1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - General, R, 1921-1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - General, S, 1929-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - General, V-Y, 1924-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - African Sculpture, circa 1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Albers, Josef, circa 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Bagdatopoulos, William Spencer, 1929-1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Ballin, Hugo, 1934-1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Band, Max, 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Barclay, McClelland, 1931-1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Barnes, Carroll, circa 1941-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Barton, Loren, 1930-1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Beetz, Carl, 1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Bensco, Charles, 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Benson, Frank W., circa 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Bentley, John W., 1923; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Bethel, Worden, 1929-1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Biberman, Edward, 1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Blazek, Anton, 1934-1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Blumenschein, Ernest L., circa 1929; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Bodrero, James, 1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Borg, Carl Oscar, 1921-1926; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Botke, Cornelis & Jessie Arms, 1923-1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 27-29)
  - Braun, Maurice, 1924-1926; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Brown, Benjamin Chambers, 1921-1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Brunswig, Marguerite, circa 1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Buff, Conrad, 1929-1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Carrere, Fernando, 1943-1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Carroll, Bill, circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Chaliapin, Boris, 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Christy, Howard Chandler, 1924-1925; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Clark, Alson, 1921-1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Cooper, Colin Campbell, 1925-1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Cornwell, Dean, 1931-1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Cugat, Francesc, 1925-1931; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Curtis, Leland, circa 1928; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Davidson, Jo, 1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Davidson, John, 1934-1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - de Chirico, Giorgio, 1930-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Dike, Phil, 1931-1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Dixon, Maynard, 1921-1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Douglas, Haldane, 1927-1928; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Edstrom, David, 1931-1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Etching, Reference, circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Feitelson, Lorser, 1936-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Fechin, Nicolai - Correspondence, circa 1927-1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Fechin, Nicolai - Correspondence, circa 1935-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Fechin, Nicolai - Printed Material, 1912-1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Fechin, Nicolai - Photographs and Receipts, circa 1929-circa 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Garnsey, Julian E., circa 1926; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Gauguin, Paul, 1931-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Gleason, Duncan, 1925-1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Gordon, Leon, 1928-1929; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Greenman, Frances, 1934-1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Haggin, Ben Ali, 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Hansen, Armin, 1926-1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 23-24)
  - Hansen, H.W., 1928-1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Harrison, Tom, 1932-1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Hartmann, Sadakichi, 1932-1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Heika, Earl, circa 1931; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Herter, Adele and Albert, 1927-1929; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Hubert-Robert, Marius, 1933-1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Ilyin, Gleb, circa 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Imrey, Ferenc, circa 1923; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Interior Design, 1932-1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Jacobs, Michel, circa 1931; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Janel, Emil, 1930-1931; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Jensen, Helen Webster, 1930-1931; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Johnson, Frank Tenney, 1928-1929; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Junior League of Los Angeles, 1931-1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Katchamakoff, Atanas, circa 1931-1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 39-40)
  - Keith, William, 1927-1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Klee, Paul, 1941-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Kleitsch, Joseph, circa 1922-1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 43-44)
  - Kleitsch, Joseph, circa 1922-1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Knight, Aston, 1907-1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 2-4)
  - Kosa, Jr., Emil, 1932-1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Krasnow, Peter, 1922-1931; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Kutcher, Ben, 1925-1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Labaudt, Lucien, circa 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Leger, Fernand, 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Leighton, Kathryn Woodman, 1925-1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Llopis, C. Ruano, circa 1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Los Angeles Museum, 1926-1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Lovet-Lorski, Boris, circa 1935-1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Lukits, Theodore Nikolai, 1930-1931; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - MacDonald-Wright, Stanton, 1932-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Messick, Ben, 1938-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Mac-Gurrin, Buckley, 1933-1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Moore, Henry, circa 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Moore, Philip, 1931; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Moran, Thomas, 1925-1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Morgan, Theo J., 1927; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Morgenstiern, Elias Feodorovich, 1927; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Municipal Art Commission, 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Nesbitt, Phil, 1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - New York Public Library, 1912; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 25)